[Music]
y think too small I got Big Dreams you
just starting them way ahead at the end
scenes started reading and dodging all
of the quick sches money like your
[Music]
Spotify hi I'm Sarah and I'm Daniel this
is episode 14 of the dealmakers podcast
and today we are with Todd Steinberg
Todd of Thrive Financial Group is a
broker that specializes in accounting
practice sales and has been doing that
for what he claims as over 30 years
which is a lot of years for the age that
you are Todd so welcome we're glad to
have you thank you yeah I'm 75 years old
so yeah I've been doing this since I was
45 uh no I am um it it is crazy to think
it been that long but the the truth of
the matter is I I was 16 U believe it or
not when I started in the accounting uh
Consulting industry as fate would have
it my next door neighbor was the founder
of a consulting firm that specialized in
helping accounting firms grow and at the
time you I just was a kid looking for a
summer job and our office was around the
corner so I actually would ride my bike
to work didn't know what the business
was but I started as the kind of guinea
pig putting brochures together making
copies um next thing you know I'm going
to school for business and marketing
marting and make a long story short I
spent the next 25 years at that
organization kind of from the uh ous to
the to the penthouse if you will uh
became the Vice President of Sales um
and essentially what we did was we
trained accounting firms imagine this
teaching accountants how to sell that
was our mission um so we had our work
cut out for us and I mean that with all
due respect it was a it was a great run
we would pack a room full of accountants
every month with about 30 CPAs EAS tax
professionals from all over the country
and it was like sales and marketing for
dummies like this is what you say this
is what you don't say this is how you go
out and bring in business clients um
what I didn't realize at the time that
which has ultimately led me to my career
today at TH Financial Group is many of
the clients that I was helping them
build their accounting
practices fast forward couple decades
later uh now they're ready to retire
relocate get involved in other business
interests so I found myself in a very
natural position to bring buyers and
sellers together so while I no longer am
a marketing consultant that ship has
sailed th Financial Group for the last
five years has specialized exclusively
in working with accountants um to help
them buy and sell practices across the
country
primarily uh 500,000 to 5 million in
Revenue so um that's the experience that
I bring to the table during those 25
years at the other firm I should
indicate that I I started selling
accounting firm since 1999 so I wasn't
quite um 30 years or 16 when I started
doing that but I was only about 21 so
you know that's still pretty good in my
book so I prefer to imagine you as a
16-year-old like going door too and
trying to sell an accounting
practice you got like Girl Scout cookies
wrapping paper and a
p&l so with our with our focus on
Acquisitions I mean we're going to spend
a lot of time talking about business
brokering and and selling but so before
we get into all that I wanted to spend a
little time on the Consulting that you
did for so long um the industry has
changed so much over the the last two or
three decades so I mean it's just a
amazing to me you've seen so many
different iterations of of how you sell
a market accounting services how you
package accounting services and I
remember from our first call you guys
were the ones that kind of pioneered the
the monthly reoccurring Revenue model is
that right yeah it was a little before
our time it was kind of value billing
before that was a term so what we had
created was and this was being taught to
accountants all the way back to
1991 where we had a package of services
that was designed for small business
owners so there's about 16 items on
there in that agreement that for a a
fixed monthly fee and this was before
the days of a and direct draft so we
actually go pick up a check from the
client but every month for the
maintenance of that accounting system
they would pay us a monthly fee and that
accounting bookkeeping right up is what
we would call it uh was really the main
focus so small to mediumsized business
owners anywhere from you know startup
companies to maybe 20 employees those
that would Outsource their accounting
controls to a firm a small to midsize
accounting firm with maybe 1 to 19
employees uh we were extremely
successful in teaching accountants how
to generate those leads this was back
when like appointment setting doing
telemarketing before the the internet
and payperclick and social media um and
digital advertising was even a thing so
yeah I I have seen a lot of iterations
and and changes but one thing that's
been consistent throughout the years is
that small to midsize firms still value
you today as much as they did 30 years
ago having a good book of recurring
monthly business clients it opens up the
door to sell other additional services
today whether that's advisory whether
that's wealth management whether that's
payroll obviously income tax preparation
is something that if you've got them as
a monthly client chances are you're
doing their business return and their
personal tax return so yeah um I mean
the the core concept of like why people
need it and some of the sales processes
still work today how people generate
leads and and ultimately how they're
being serviced of course that that's
changed dramatically I'm so glad that
we're having you uh we that we have you
on as a guest I'm so glad we're talking
about this now because this is an area
that I underserve people I own an
accounting firm uh got into business
brokering late last year so just a
minute ago and uh so many so so many
people come to me because they are
looking to buy firms like Sarah was
saying you know everyone wants an off
Market accounting firm um but I come
from virtual firms like just from
basically from the get-go so I just
don't real I never realized I have to
like train my mind to to realize and
understand that there are firms out
there that aren't package this way they
aren't selling services in this way and
um that's a major opportunity for
somebody looking to acquire you buy a
firm like this you can overhaul it um
have a really valuable acquisition on
your hands so great call out on on how
and and I'm assuming you still see this
today that that firms are still you know
not taking advantage of these lessons
that you're talking about right yeah I
mean even the the traditional brick and
mortar serving clients acquiring that
way things really even 10 15 years ago
when portals and cloud and things really
became prevalent that really went on
warp speed when Co hit so even
traditional firms now that have clients
that are 5 minutes down the road that
they would visit them a few years ago or
the clients would come into the office
in many cases
now it who wants to go deal with traffic
and and rain and snow when you can just
jump on a a zoom meeting uh or
communicate in a web portal or or via
email as necessary so it shifted I mean
even a lot of the sellers that I'm
talking to that are sort of old school
um that built a traditional CPA firm the
oldfashioned way um in the last few
years um they they've adopted and their
client have adopted to be able to work
with them in a more technology forward
way there are certainly virtual firms
that were designed and built from the
ground up that way um but I'm finding
that um many of the the firms that I'm
talking with you know small to midsize
firms that are looking to retire
relocate or sell for various reasons um
while many of them still have a physical
office presence um I I asked them well
does your staff come in not really do
clients ever come in no not really do do
you really need the office probably not
um so there's maybe a few older clients
that still like to come in and sit down
and talk about their you know personal
problems with the accountant as they get
their taxes done but those are few and
far between anymore so I'd say most of
the practices that that I'm talking with
are are definitely changed with the
times I had a call yesterday with
somebody who um uh their whole business
model is pulling in or acquiring at like
05x these poorly run practices that are
all you know in person and there's uh
they have you know QuickBooks desktop
and um you know pulls them in grabs them
at a really discounted rate and then uh
makes it all you know systematized over
the course of two years and then sells
it for like one one and a half X and
that's their whole business just turning
around a couple years ago I had a a
listing it was a great practice
profitable good client mix sellers
available for Trans all the things that
a buyer would want problem was they were
in Bluefield West Virginia now I dare
you to even try to find that on the map
I mean it was it's a really small town
and it required a physical presence
somebody had to be there this was like
2017 2018 pre-co we had a really hard
time in fact we were unable to locate a
buyer for that practice despite the fact
that it had a lot of positives fast
forward to last year I have a client in
somewhere in Arkansas I mean it was
extremely rural I was like oh I have
another blue field on my hands here but
this practice was 100% virtual even
though the accountant sat in Arkansas
the clients were all over the place and
when we marketed this thing as a virtual
firm I it was unbelievable I mean we had
offers coming in from all over the
country uh it was a hot commodity and we
were able to sell that practice for a
premium price all because of of their
business model they were just as
profitable as any other firm um client
mix nothing special but it was virtual
so uh there was just a ton of interest
and and if one can if anyone's listening
to this and they're thinking about how
they can set up their practice certainly
you're opening up your your business to
the masses if you're able to do
something like that and make those those
changes so there there's something I
want to go back to real quick but first
if you're if this is the first time
you've uh seen dealmakers podcast if uh
if this sounds valuable to you
uh go ahead and like subscribe uh you
know drop in the comments if you have
any questions that we can address on a
followup um but something I I want to
make sure we go back on so Sarah you
mentioned 0. 5x Todd you know point you
know 1X um what are we talking about
there for new listeners that maybe don't
know how accounting firms are valued I
generally see firms trading for
somewhere between 1X to
1.5x 1.5 is rare similar in the middle
is more typical 1.2
1.25 um that's a multiple of multiple of
Revenue or sales not eida not sde we
could have a whole other podcast about
why firms are valued that way versus
other businesses but this is the way
it's been since uh I was a little
16-year-old um riding my bike to work so
that that has not changed um there are
typically When I Look to value a a
practice and doing a valuation there's
typically four main factors that are
drivers to valuations those are and
these are in no particular order
location client mix profitability and
transition assistance from the seller
and I would also lump in staff with
transition assistance who's going to be
staying on to help this feel more like a
merger than an acquisition so when all
those things are taken in consideration
you're usually going to end up somewhere
in that 1 to 1.5 range with most falling
around one and a quarter let me give you
an example and ask a question here just
so you know one because I need the
answer to this question but two so that
our listeners can get some more value
from this maybe even conceptualize this
a little bit better I had a initial
seller interview with a firm I'm looking
at yesterday uh Topline sales is just
shy of 4 million asking or sorry Topline
sales is yeah justy of 4 million asking
price is
4.8 uh sde is 600
so we were at like it was like 1.5x
gross give or take some something like
that but six and a half times SD which
is just you know crazy compared to other
industries that aren't valued based on
Topline so do you ever consider a
multiple of SD or is it always a
percentage of Topline sales
profitability is a factor there's no
question but I'll give an example to
illustrate why it's not the end all be
all I could have well it's just use your
example of a $4 million firm right I
maybe I have two firms one of them is
600 what did you say that the SD was was
it 600,000 about 600 600,000 okay and
let's say we have one4 million firm
that's got SD of 600,000 we have another
firm that's also generating 4 million
that has SD of let's say 1.2 million
twice that the first practice that has
SD of
600,000 that owner or partner or
Partners potentially at that size they
like to take a lot of time off maybe
they take nine weeks vacation per year
maybe they're billable hours or a
thousand hours a year maybe they have
class A office space maybe they have a
really talented staff that they slightly
overpay because they're good and they've
been with the firm for
years over here on the other side you
have a a $4 million practice hire SD at
1 .2 million but Class C office space
the owners are doing a lot of the work
you've got a staff that's got a lot of
turnover uh maybe they don't use the
latest and greatest Tech stack like the
other firm does and they pay to play
with the best software in the industry
my point here is beauty lies in the eye
of the beholder which practice is more
valuable I mean one might look at the
first practice a and think that's the
better route one might look at practice
B and think that's the better route so I
don't like to look at sde until I really
understand the Dynamics of the practice
in Greater detail before I'm willing to
say this is a better practice than that
you must have seen a few of these over
the last 30 years because you hit the
nail in the head with practice a you
perfectly described it so thank you oh
really okay nice work pad he's like yeah
I know that exact one prob no um it
seems like there's only so many
um that's interesting because the SD
multiple that's a low SD it seems like
for four million but uh it would kind of
come out in the wash a little bit if
you're looking at allomer buyers who are
reliant on SBA financing right because
they're not GNA Buble to get as much
yeah financing support so um they want
to have a broader cash flow margin and
then that reduces your potential buyers
so that reduces the demand and then
therefore would kind of reduce the the
price it probably goes for yeah I mean
you're you're 100% right cash flow
lenders are going to look at that and it
could be
problematic I'll give another example if
like I have a practice in California
right now it's a great firm on the
surface you have it's about 3 million in
Revenue they've got about 1.3 they're
dropping to the bottom line W this is a
great firm problem is you have four
partners that are all in the trenches
killing themselves to do the work so now
we have to replace four people that want
to retire um and that can be done but
that's not an easy task and you've got a
tremendous amount of people that are
expressing interest in this firm because
it's profitable and it's in a good
location and all these other factors but
then when you boil down to how are we
going to actually make this transition
work with four highlevel people that
Serv as very technical type clients
partly why they're profitable because
you need a very high level of expertise
and skill set to be able to do that work
this this thing has been sitting on the
market for a couple of months now longer
than than one would have anticipated um
because there's some of the challenges
in being being able to actually deliver
and the sellers are saying well you got
to be able to replace me how are you
going to be able to do that um and
that's a question that most most firms
can't ask can't answer we're replacing
one person that's great we're replacing
two three four when you start to get
into that couple million dollar in
revenue or larger range again I I I
usually max out at about5 Mill ion um so
you know top 100 top 250 firms that's
not my space but in a one to four
partner firm which is typically what I'm
dealing with this is something you have
to factor in I see that a good deal too
with a retirement uh age folks who are
hanging on because they have so much
expertise they want like we talk about
all the time they want to preserve their
legacy and make sure their clients are
taken care of um and they can't find
it's not like they're just willing to
sell to somebody they really need the
seller
or the buyer to sell them on how they're
going to take care of their employees
and how they're going to take care of um
their clients and it can be pretty hard
to convince somebody who's got you know
40 years well I mean you have 30 years
right so um 70 years of experience
in sophisticated you know it could be
hard to convince them that you're going
to able to come in no matter who you are
and do as good of a job as them so you
know by hes that's a pain point that I
see a lot right now because um it's it's
kind of a lot of these listings have uh
hit the market in the accounting
practice world because it's you know may
late May and that's um a lot of buyers
are reaching out to me I'm sure they are
to you Todd and saying hey do you know
of any good listings I'm looking to buy
um I would love your take on some of the
things people can do to be appealing in
that P from that angle I think I'm on
search funer I'm on all these kind of
community groups where I don't think the
potential buyers or the Searchers are uh
realizing that they need to be
salespeople themselves when they're you
know entering into this sphere and
they're not necessarily focusing on what
they're bringing to the table as a
potential buyer they're not making smart
calculated choices when they reach out
to Brokers bankers lawyers um what are
some things that a buyer does that just
makes you write them off Todd it's
starts really with the sellers and what
I mean by that is that everyone that is
looking to find a successor has
different priorities in what they're
looking for from a buyer you know for
for example um and this is the majority
of the sellers they want somebody who is
going to take good care of their clients
and their staff that that's like
priority number one the economics that's
certainly an important factor but
finding somebody that they can rest
their head on the pillow at night
knowing that they left their clients and
their staff in a good spot that that is
the most important thing to to these
accounting firms and the to the sellers
um there are some that it's show me the
money I want the best possible price I
want the best possible terms yeah they
care it's not that they don't care but
it's not on the top of their priority
list so that can those priorities will
be slightly different from firm to firm
a as a
buyer depending on what your background
is so to answer your question this I'm
I'm finding now in in 2024 that I can
lump my buyers into really two
categories one of them is financial like
these are the PE firms these are the
folks with Deep Pockets that want to get
into if maybe they're already in and
have a platform and they're looking to
build it out or maybe they're trying to
to get in and this this is about half of
my buyers that have never run an
accounting firm they do not know a debit
from a credit um in that they are
looking to invest in an accounting
practice that's great and I think it's
an awesome model for a multitude of
reasons um and it's why so many of them
are coming into our space um those are
the financial buyers then there are the
Strategic buyers which are the existing
accountants or accounting firms that
look at this and say okay well we can
consolidate our firms together have a
better client experience we bring in
some Talent uh you know this would be a
great fit economies of scale so finding
what is um the the right opportunity for
a particular seller I can't give advice
to a buyer um unless I knew who what
firm they're looking at um because they
might not even be able to get their foot
in the door if it's a firm that would
only prefer to sell to an existing CPA
or CPA firm and that's a lot of them so
if you're an investor or somebody with a
business background that wants to into
the space you're going to have a hard
time um even getting your foot in the
door because there's U there's not
really an interest on the other side to
talk with you whether that's right wrong
or indifferent whether you have a good
business plan or not alternatively there
might be some firms out there as a
seller that are thinking okay I want to
sell only to an existing firm that's got
a large infrastructure or you know what
I'm I'm just a one person firm or
two-person firm where somebody coming
out of Industry big four or private as
long as they can go get a good SBA loan
or they've got the ability to put in a a
solid um a solid down payment whether
that's through third party financing
through one of our preferred Partners um
or their own personal resources then
then they might be in a good spot I
would just say that anybody should have
a one-page buyer summary so that if
you're talking with a broker like me you
have something outside of just a
LinkedIn profile or a website that talks
about what your objectives are talks
about your vision so that we can at
least get you in a zoom meeting meeting
with a with a potential seller as a
first step to give you an opportunity to
shine so without a summary you you've
got nine or t buyers out there for every
practice that's for sale and that's me
being kind there's probably more like 15
or 20 it's like a Feeding Frenzy um so
if we have something that we can share
that paints you in a positive light
you're not for everybody and everybody's
not for you but there will be firms and
opportunities out there that could
potentially be a good fit for you I
think that your highl lighting you know
maybe generously so you have two
different groups that you put in you
have financial and you have strategic
but search funders are really common
which are I guess in the financial
category there but they're you know
regular entrepreneurs who are uh hanging
out and looking for a business to buy
and you know maybe they're self-funded
so they have some savings that they are
living off of while they do this or
they're working while they're doing it
but you know sometimes they've raised a
bunch of capital and they're sitting
there searching for a firm but usually
they don't have any accounting
experience sometimes they do and almost
immediately they realize like I should
focus on buying an accounting practice
this is a great opportunity for me which
I think is genius um but uh you know
they don't they don't always have
anything in the background and I have
just had so many tonu reach outs now
from folks who say I'm looking to buy an
accounting practice like you know send
me any ones that you might have or um I
had a straightup call with somebody who
ended it saying could you perform a
bunch of cold calls for me and deliver
me three potential firms that you think
would be a good fit for my requirements
and that's not what I do at all I'm a
lawyer you know and also that's not what
a broker does I don't know anyone who
serves that function and it's a total
misre of the market where there's 15 to
20 buyers for every seller and like
interested buyers for every seller
so you know this tonee type of reaching
out um can be somewhat alleviated by
just the thought exercise of what are
these sellers actually interested in I
mean beyond the the Topline purchase
price that you're offering you know they
care about their employees their clients
their reputation and the biggest concern
that most of them have is how are you
going to take care of my clients if you
don't have this experience so if your
summary isn't Sol in that issue or
connecting those dots for them I think
you're going to really have a hard time
getting across the threshold of even
getting a zoom meeting there are some
sellers that and I have an example right
now A A two-partner firm they don't want
to retire um they have gotten the
business to the point that they have
built a
beautiful organization they make a good
living but to get it to the next level
they feel like they need to take on an
investment and they need to bring on
some leadership and and maybe that's not
the CPA strong suit is developing it's
hard to take a firm from let's just say
4 million to 20 million or from 20
million to 150 million and sometimes it
makes sense to bring on an investment
with some capital and some people that
have a a CEO mindset that can really
help take the business to the next level
so you're starting to see deals now
where if if a seller wants to stay on
maybe they roll some Equity into the
deal and to taking a substantial cash up
up front and maybe some level of a of a
seller note um so there's opportunities
like that I think it's harder for a
financial buyer to come in and replace a
retiring or somebody who's jumping has
to jump ship within the next 12 months
uh whether it's for a health problem
retirement other business interests
those are the ones that are going to
look you in the eye in an initial
meeting and say how are you going to
replace me I okay I understand you're
willing to pay my price but who's going
to Champion in this effort on day one or
in 60 days or in 90 days and the answer
of oh well we'll we'll figure that out
or we'll hire that person that doesn't
really make firms confident and
comfortable unfortunately that's true I
mean the we'll figure it out will hire
something really uh Falls flat for a lot
of people in the industry in any
industry maybe right now because if
you've tried to hire anyone recently is
really challenging um so I think a lot
of people who do sell have gone through
the process of trying to hire people to
replace them it hasn't succeeded so
unless you have somebody on staff or
somebody you can point to that you've
already designated who's going to be
able to be your tax manager or what have
you um I think my the people I've talked
to are pretty dubious when that's the
plan yeah I'd say come come to the
broker or come to the attorney with what
that plan is and who that person is it's
not to say that they can't figure it out
and many of them will and would and
probably will will get a chance to do
that but if if you're the reality is if
you're up against 10 or 15 quality
buyers and you don't have that plan or
you don't have that
person you're you're going to get lost
in the shuffle unfortunately because
somebody right behind you has that
person identified and it's a sure thing
versus the the Hope or promise that we
we'll find them uh together so in in
your experience with all the deals that
you've worked on who's the impediment
here the seller or the buyers I don't
know that I would say that either or an
impediment I just think it's about fit
um and every one of them is is unique
every seller has certain checklist of
things that are on their wish list or
dream list and priority list and and
every buyer so you know you're not for
everybody everybody's not for you
somebody might be the perfect buyer for
one firm and you know they're not for
the other so I would just say know what
you're looking at as as a buyer you've
got to look at the initial Sim offering
memorandum and be able to say okay this
is how I would be able to execute almost
like a mini business plan of of how this
would work and what this would look like
because they're going to get grilled by
somebody like me or by the seller in an
initial meeting on how are you before we
even get into terms like how would this
work how can you how is this going to
happen so uh I just think it's finding
the right the right match it is a bit of
a matchmaking process I I I sometimes
view myself in that light um and that I
yes I'm an intermediary yes here to
negotiate price and terms but there's so
many things personality culture level of
service that all need to really fall in
line so a lot of stars need to line up
for it to be the right deal for both
parties there's a lot of people out
there that are looking for accounting
firms right now that are feeling like
things are pretty bleak maybe they don't
have an accounting background and
they're just getting beat up by sellers
or uh they do have an accounting
background and they're they're just not
finding the right firm and I mean I love
that we're ending like we're coming in
into like an optimistic tone here um
because you know it's I think that from
what I've seen it's the people that are
stressed the people that feel like it
can't be done that they're ready to give
up it's because they've spent too much
time on the wrong deal you know if
somebody wants you to move across the
country go look at another firm like
just just move on like if you're not
moving and they want you to move just go
talk to somebody else like just don't
don't beat your head against the wall if
they want you to be a CPA go talk to
somebody else you know it's just not
it's not worth the wear and tear yeah
it's the timeline that has been getting
people there hasn't you know because of
tax season there hasn't been much on the
market so people have been really trying
to make bad fits fit um because that's
the only thing they see so hopefully in
a couple months people feel a little bit
more optimistic when there's more going
on but I like that you were into the
optimistic tone Daniel because I was GNA
take a turn and be like like Downer so
typical Ty I'm yeah I'm such a downer um
but Todd you know you said a lot of
things there's a like I always say
there's a lid for every pot you know and
I think that's beautiful and certainly a
good party line but there has to be like
a profile of a buyer that just is not a
good fit for anyone like just they're
all red flags they're no
Solutions so what makes somebody just a
bad buyer just not being educated on
what they're looking to get themselves
into so for example if I have somebody
that says yeah yeah I want to buy a
practice and I want to don't put any
money down and I want to buy that based
on collections over five years and I'll
say you've got no chance whether it's
through me or or anybody else for that
matter firms are just not selling that
way and they try to justify the
valuation so whether it's Thrive or any
of the other great brokers in the
industry know what the market is and be
ready to to to play with fair market
value nobody's going to try to
you know generate a sale for a business
that that's not worth the price so I
think that's the first thing and then
also I think you've got to be able to
explain your vision I mean yes there is
like a sales aspect to being likable and
and having having the seller feel that
this is a this is going to be a good
match uh for their clients and their
staff like you've got to be able to step
into that seller shoes if you're going
to be an owner operator um so
unfortunately people that maybe have
great technical skills but they're maybe
they're just not have to ask themselves
like are they good business people are
are they leaders can they think about
their business like a CEO as instead of
maybe buying yourself a job uh which I
think some people do try and and
ultimately um that becomes problematic
and and prohibits the deal from from
going through so you know I I've seen a
lot of buyers that um will say the wrong
thing and we we could probably do
another two hour podcast on what not to
say in an missal seller meeting um but
as long as you remain kind of true to
yourself and you know B business-wise
you're you're doing the right things
you're you're you're going into this
with an informed educated you know
talking to people like Thrive or Sarah
or or getting a pre-qual from a banker
you know just being prepared so that
when you do take those meetings um
you're you're in a spot to to shine I
really love how you uh gave us those
those four key uh elements you look at
when valuing a firm and I also feel like
you touched on something where you know
if you if you want to be a buyer of a
firm regardless of your background you
need to have a good a good buyer profile
a good one pager um what are some some
really great things or or what are the
essentials that need to be in that
profile in that one pager to make it uh
viable to to that you would want to
present to a seller what what has to be
there yeah I think it's half mini resume
you know where where where you were what
you've done and then half like a vision
statement this is my mission statement
this is what I'm trying to accomplish
I'd like to have you know 20 million in
Revenue within the next X amount of
years looking for firms uh like this
location agnostic or you know Southern
California whatever you're looking for
doesn't need to be more than one page
maybe two I and I see these every day
and and usually it's it's some level of
a resume SL vision statement of what
they're looking to accomplish is there
anything that they should absolutely not
put into this I I don't know that I
would
um would say that there's nothing that
they they shouldn't put in i' say just
remain true to yourself and what you're
trying to do and and where where you've
been and where you're headed and look
again I've said this a couple times it's
not a fit like you're not for everyone
everyone's not for you so if this one
isn't a Fit U maybe the next one will be
you can see why I like working with Todd
cuz he's like you know it's important to
get a really good match and very
ethically you know minded there's buyer
and seller don't mislead anyone about
what you're actually looking for um
because you know there's probably a good
fit where they'd be into that um so I
think that's a really nice ethos to see
in a broker but I have things I think
you should leave it
on well I was about to say I I think
Todd's changing some of the advice that
we've given on this very podcast you
know there's been plenty of episodes
where we have said do not talk about
offshoring in your initial seller
meetings and uh I Todd I I like your
perspective better that you know be true
to yourself if that's your game plan
then you know maybe it does make sense
just to tell them about it I don't think
that's a dirty word anymore um it's not
taboo like it was 10 years ago I mean if
you're GNA acquire scale in my
experience you know the big firms have
been doing out out offshoring or
Outsourcing for years but I could see
where maybe that would rub somebody the
wrong way if they don't do that or have
strong feelings against that but if
ultimately that's your plan anyway then
you know you're you're setting yourself
up for failure if if you're not going to
be transparent about that and then
you're going to go do it anyway and that
that might not go over well so I don't
know I mean that's just that that's my
personal feelings on on Outsourcing but
I'm sure there are there are other uh
Sarah do not dos so I'd love to hear
what some of those
are well no you're coming from the
perspective of having you know sellers
that have a lot of interest in buyers so
when you're a buyer you know let's also
not forget that Brokers you know we want
the deal to get done attorneys they get
paid regardless oh yeah yeah that's uh I
wish that were true perhaps you should
do my collections
Daniel um no I mean from a buyer's
perspective you just don't know what
they're what's going to rub them the
wrong way so I like to I I think it's
nice when you see ones that are tailored
to the the target like oh I'm looking
for a California firm that's owned by
like the example you gave like four
partners and you know that can be really
like okay they took the time to look at
this and make this unique and you know
bespoke and then the vision statement
you have to be really careful not to
insult anyone because if you're going to
change you're G to tell somebody like
you're going to change what they've been
doing for their whole career that's that
can be perceived poorly you know you're
all right in that I I have this lens
because I work with a seller they pay my
fee I have a fiduciary resp
responsibility to the seller so my
mindset is let's let's let's see buyers
in all their good Bad and the Ugly and
if they're not the right fit next let's
talk to the next girl right so it's like
I'm churning through buyers all day long
to try to find that right fit so that's
why I I do see myself more of like a
Matchmaker than trying to like help a
buyer buy something that I don't think
in the long term is going to be great
for my client there's so many things
here that we've touched on like we
really could do a twoh hour podcast I
think on this because there's so many
things I want to drill down into but I'm
also watching the clock um Todd I want
to make sure I give you plenty of time
uh to to talk to the audience talk to
the world this is going to live on uh on
YouTube and on the podcast platforms so
who do you serve who do you want to help
how can they reach out to you what what
can you offer them through our financial
group we we specialize in working with
accountant that's the only industry that
I deal with I'm a very much a specialist
um and I've carved out that 500,000 to
about 5 million in Revenue range is the
types of firms that are typically being
represented by my organization um while
I do work with uh sellers primarily you
know for me finding somebody who's even
considering what succession might look
like even if that doesn't mean listing
their firm for a few years I'm happy to
have that conversation because for
anyone who's in practice at some point
you're going to need to cash in your
chips right you're going to want to get
the best possible price terms and fit
that process of planning to exit starts
now so what you think your exit might be
in terms of how much time you're going
to spend what the terms might be that
might be a little different than what
I'm seeing out there in the marketplace
so I'm happy to talk with anybody who's
considering uh succession planning or
just wants to be educated on that
subject matter on the other side of
course we're looking for qualified
buyers I mean I have listings currently
on my site and that's updated daily with
anything new new that comes on or
something's going off because it's sold
so you're welcome to go to my site and
bookmark that check it periodically for
any new listings that I receive register
as a qualified buyer and um I'll do my
best to be your Matchmaker so yeah I'll
leave it there perfect I mean just
recently like over the last couple of
days I've had I've seen brokers in the
uh the
ibba um Facebook group and uh in the
business brokers of Florida looking for
or a broker looking for someone who
specialized in accounting firms so you
are are in a great Niche I'm glad to
have you here um bonus content over 30
years have you have you been approached
to sell other businesses have you sold
other businesses or do you stay strict
on that Niche you know I I use this
analogy that I try to go a mile deep and
an inch wide versus a mile wide and an
inch deep so let think about that for a
second so I I don't want to be a
generalist I want to be be the guy who
knows everything and anything that I
possibly can about my space so I I've
been approached to sell other businesses
I don't want to do it um I like what I
do I have enough to keep me busy uh I
consider myself a boutique firm with me
and a couple of people and um things are
good so why change fantastic fantastic
so at the top of the call we talked
about what goes into valuing a firm at
the end of toward the end of the the
call we we talked about how to position
yourself as a a buyer
um so much value in between for buyers
and sellers uh thank you so much Todd uh
if you got value from this podcast
please like And subscribe to uh hear
more from other dealmakers in the
industry if you want to get in touch
with Todd to list your firm or to to uh
buy a firm his contact details will be
in the show notes below uh so as always
thanks for listening and Todd thanks for
joining us we'll have to have you back
soon Daniel Sarah thank you so much for
the opportunity to be with you guys I
had a lot of fun and it's been great so
I appreciate the opportunity all right
it's been episode 14 of the dealmakers
podcast
[Music]
thanks do it bigger than anybody ever